RG 089:024, Connecticut Transportation Authority
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut Transportation Authority records
1956-1973
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Transportation Authority
27 cubic feet
The Connecticut Transportation Authority was established in 1963, per P.A. 639. In 1969 it merged into the new Department of Transportation, per P.A. 768, sec. 9, and was incorporated into the Bureau of Rail and Motor Carrier Services.
RG089_024
1991-023 and 1992-006
Historical Note
The Connecticut Transportation Authority was established in 1963, per P.A. 639, to preserve and improve essential rail services threatened with cessation resulting from the financial problems of the New Haven Railroad. In 1969 it merged into the new Department of Transportation, per P.A. 768, sec. 9, and was incorporated into the Bureau of Rail and Motor Carrier Services.
See also the.
Scope and Content
These records consist of two accessions. The first is an unprocessed accession that includes material dating 1956-1973: correspondence, Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, Tri-State Transportation Commission reports, Penn Central Transportation Company material, and New Haven R.R. reorganization material. The second accession is Executive Director Samuel Kannell’s administrative files, 1963-1971 that includes Governor’s Office memoranda and correspondence, and material relating to the Capitol Region Transportation Task Force, Penn Central Transportation Company, Tri-State Transportation Commission, Northeastern Regional Transportation Committee, and New York Metropolitan Transportation Authority.
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Related Material
RG 089, Dept. of Transportation, 1941-2003, bulk 1973-2003
RG 089:001, State Highway Department, 1894-1975
RG 089:010, State Boundary Line Perambulations, 1965-1997
RG 089:011, Aerial photographs, see the Research Guide to Aerial Photographs at the Connecticut State Library
RG 089:030, State Traffic Commission, 1935-1995
RG 089:031, Connecticut Public Transportation Commission, 1980-2001
RG 089:032, Transportation Accountability Board, 1986-1987
RG 089:037, Commissioners of Steamship Terminals, 1915
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Bureau of Rail and Motor Carrier Services; Connecticut. Transportation Authority; Connecticut. Dept. of Transportation; United States. Interstate Commerce Commission; Tri-State Transportation Commission
Subjects:
Penn Central Transportration Company; New York and New Haven Railroad Company; Railroads -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Correspondence; Dockets; Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Accession: 1991-023, 1956-1973
  This accession is unprocessed. The following is a rough description.
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Louis T. Klauder and Associates, Consulting Engineers. Preliminary Specifications for Electric Multiple-Unit Cars for Operation on the New Haven Railroad: A Consultant's Report to the Tri-State Transportation Commission, undated; 27 copies (Box 2)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1962, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Tri-State Transportation Commission project reviews, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous proposals and specifications, 1965-1967 (Box 5)
  - Tri-State Transortation Commission studies, 1967-1968 (Box 6)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1960-1968, undated (Box 7)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Memoranda to Connecticut Transportation Authority members, 1964-1968 (Box 8)
  - Connecticut Transportation Authority meeint notices, agendas, minutes, 1965-1968 (Box 8)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Legislative material, 1967-1969 (Box 9)
  - Report of the Year 1964 of the Connecticut Transportation Authority (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1969-1972 (Box 9)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission, 1956-1965 (Box 10)
  - Contract between State of New Jersey and Pennsylvania Railroad (Box 11)
  - Penn Central Company organization (Box 11)
  - Reports (Box 11)
  - Penn Central Company New Haven Region - Meetings with N.H. RR Trustees, Conn., N.Y., R.I., Mass, etc. (Box 11)
  - Interim operation service, West End Contract between Tri-State Transportation Commissin and New Haven Railroad (Box 11)
  - Interim operationg agreement compliance with standards of service (Box 11)
  - Contract negotiations between Pennsylvania and New York Central Railroad Companies (Box 11)
  - Penn Central Company fare rescheduling (Box 11)
  - Penn Central Company New Haven region passenger service data (Box 11)
  - S. Kannell correspondence, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1963-1965 (Box 12)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1959-1968, undated (Box 13)
  - Tri-State Transportation Commission technical reports, 1968-1969 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1958-1968, undated (Box 13)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1965-1968 (Box 14)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1962-1968 (Box 15)
  - Meeting notices and minutes, 1965-1966, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Dept. of Transportation Bureau of Highways - General file, 1967-1969 (Box 16)
  - Reorganization of New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad company material, 1963-1968, undated (Box 16)
  - Dept. of Transportation Bureau of Highways liason meetings (Box 16)
  - Dept. of Transportation Bureau of Highways certification, compliance with Special Act No.412 (Box 16)
  - Railroad passenger facilities statewide (Box 16)
  - Correspondence - General files 1 and 2, 1960-1969 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence - interoffice, 1963-1967 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence - Congressional, 1967-1968 (Box 18)
  - Congressional file, 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - Myer Feldman, Esq. - Correspondence, memoranda, etc. (Box 18)
  - Connecticut Blue Cross, 1965-1967 (Box 18)
  - Connecticut Medical Service (CMS), 1965-1967 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence - General file 3, 1967-1968 (Box 18)
  - Reorganization of New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad company material, 1963-1965, undated (Box 18)
  - Tri-State Transportation Commission reports, 1965-1966, undated (Box 19)
  - Reports of Trustees to Judge Anderson - New Haven Railroad reorganization, 1962-1966 (Box 20)
  - Tax claim, 1969-1973 (Box 20)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit - New Haven Railroad, 1968-1971 (Box 20)
  - New Haven Railroad reorganization, No. 30226, 1970-1971 (Box 20)
  - Special master report - Judge John van Voorhis - New Haven Railroad reorganization, 1968 (Box 20)
  - United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, 1969-1970 (Box 20)
  - Civ. 5200 and 5210, Civ. 11 and 12 (Consolidated actions), 1968-1969 (Box 20)
  - New Haven railroad reorganization - No. 30226, Petition for Order No. 595, 1970 (Box 20)
  - United States Supreme Court, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Nos. 914, 915, 916, 917, 920, 921, 1038 and 1057 New Haven inclusion cases before the Supreme Court of the United States, 1970 (Box 20)
  - Mailing lists, U.S. Supreme Court, U.S. District Court, 1966-1967, undated (Box 20)
  - Correspondence Nos. 778, 778, 830, 831, 832, 833, 834, 835, 836, 1967-1970 (Box 20)
  - New Haven railroad reorganization - No. 30226, Petition for Order No. 595, 1970-1971 (Box 20)
  - New Haven railroad reorganization - No. 30226, Petition for Order No. 595, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence (Box 21)
  - Historical documents, 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Reports and historical documents - Connecticut Transportation Authority Volume I (Box 22)
  - Reports and historical documents - Connecticut Transportation Authority Volume II (Box 22)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission dockets, 1965-1966 (Box 23)
- Executive Director Samuel Kanell administrative files, 1963-1971; 1992-006
  - Capitol Region Transportation Task Force, 1971 (Box 1)
  - National Transportation Needs Study - Correspondence, 1970 November - 1971 Auguse; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Routes & rates, 1970-1971; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Reports and manuals, 1966-1971 (Box 1)
  - New Haven Railroad financial statements, 1964-1968 (Box 1)
  - Connecticut Research Commission (Box 2)
  - Department of Community Affairs (Box 2)
  - Penn Central Transportation Company, 1970-1971; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Tri-State Transportation Commission (Box 3)
    - Financial reports, 1964-1969; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Meeting agenda & mintues of the Commission, 1967-1969; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Monthly and annual reports, 1965-1969 (Box 3)
  - Northeastern Regional Transportation Committee (Northeast Corridor), 1965-1968 (Box 4)
  - New York Metropolitan Transportatn Authority, 1965-1968 (Box 4)
  - Governor's Office memoranda and other documents, 1963-1968 (Box 4)
  - Governor's Office corresondence, 1965-1968 (Box 4)